Franklin Society and Library Company of Lexington Records WLU Coll. 0103
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library, Special Collections and Archives
Franklin Society and Library Company of Lexington Records
1801-1891
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library, Special Collections and Archives
WLU.Coll.0103
2 Linear Feet, 43 bound ledgers
Separated Materials
Receipt dated December 2, 1841 is in the Secure Cabinet.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Franklin Society in 1891.
Scope and Contents
Includes membership records, officers' reports, business papers, subscription library records, minutes of the Society's meetings and debates. Includes receipts and letters expressing pleasure at being honored by the society. Receipt dated December 2, 1841 from Stonewall Jackson while he was a Virginia constable, which was later given to the Franklin Society.
Records; Correspondence; Literature; Societies; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Receipts (Acknowledgments); Libraries; Debates and debating; Franklin Society and Library Company of Lexington (Lexington, Va.); Jackson, Thomas Jonathan (Stonewall)
- Address; Finances; Receipts (1887), 1839-01-17; 23 Files (Box 1)
- Historical Affairs; Library Affairs; Membership Rolls, 1854-1891; 25 Files (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Historical Affairs; Library Affairs; Membership Rolls (1854-1875, 1891)
- Membership Certificates; Outside Bills; Presidents' Reports; Proceedings, 1801-1891; 23 Files (Box 3)
- Secretary's Books, 1801-1818; 5 Item (Box 4)
- Union Society; F.S. Constitution; Visitors Log; Membership Log, 1806-1896; 3 Item (Box 5)
  Union Society 1806-1808; F.S. Constitution 1838, 1857-1896; Visitors Log 1857-1875; Membership Log 1816-1888
- Secretary's Books, 1816-1830; 3 Item (Box 6)
- Secretary's Books, 1830-1845; 3 Item (Box 7)
- Secretary's Books, 1845-1860; 2 Item (Box 8)
- Secretary's Books, 1860-1886; 2 Item (Box 9)
- Secretary's Books, 1833-1891; 2 Item (Box 10)
- Treasurer's Books, 1864-1885; 3 Item (Box 11)
- Library Books; Blotter and undated Scrapbook, 1813-1846; 5 Item (Box 12)
  Library Books 1813-1823, 1827-1846; Blotter and undated Scrapbook
- Library Book; Annual Reports, 1818-1863; 2 Item (Box 13)
  Library Book (undated); Annual Reports 1818-1863
- Library Books; Roll Book, 1840-1886; 1 Item (Box 14)
  Library Books 1840-1878; Roll Book 1873-1886
- Library Books, 1847-1888; 2 Item (Box 15)
  Library Books 1847-1866, 1874-1888
- Inventory/Invoice; Treasurer's Books, 1813-1865; 5 Item (Box 16)
  Inventory/Invoice 1813-1837; Treasurer's Books 1817-31, 1844-65
- Accounts; Receipt Book, 1870-1888; 3 Item (Box 17)
  Accounts 1870-1887; Receipt Book 1873-1888
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1851-1884; 1 Files (Box 18)